Guide to the Ulster County Collection 1666-1893 (Bulk 1700-1800) MS 645
New-York Historical Society
- Series III: Militia (1787-1809)
  This series contains a small number of military documents including Regimental Orders and lists of officers and men in various companies. They are arranged in chronological sequence and are in good condition.
  - Militia Documents, 1787-1809 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Series IV: Ulster County Oversize (1710 - 1778)
  The items in this series are oversized and have been placed in special boxes. Some of them have associated wax seals. Almost all are parchment. Most are legible although several have faded ink or are discolored.
  The documents all represent 18th land transactions with one exception - Item #7 (Box 8) is a commission appointing a number of Ulster County residents as Justices of the Peace.
  - #1, Grant to Patrick McKnight. 2 pp. Includes seal and image of seal verso (3 pp.), 1719 Apr. 9 (Box 3)
  - #2, Indenture, Jacobus Kip, John Cruger, David Provoost, Phillip Van Cortlandt, John Schuyler, Oliver Schuyler, Abraham De Peyster and Cadwallader Coldin. 4 pp., 1721 Oct. 4 (Box 4)
  - #3, Land Grant to John Haskall. Includes seal. 1 p., 1719 Apr. 9 (Box 4)
  - #4, Patent to Francis Harrison, Oliver Schuyler and Allan Garratt, including survey. 2 pp., 1720 July 7 (Box 5)
  - #5, Land Grant to William Bond. Includes seal and survey. 2 pp., 1720 July (Box 6)
  - #6, Henry Wileman's Mortgage to Nathaniel Kay. 3 pp., 1727 May (Box 7)
  - #7, Commission appointing Justices of the Peace Peter Schuyler, Abraham De Peyster and others. Includes seal. I p., 1710 July 25 (Box 8)
  - #8, Indenture Elizabeth Alexander to Andreas [Maorschalk] and John Spratt. 1 p, 1730 Jan. 15 (Box 8)
  - #9, Indenture Catherine (Katherine) Alexander to Andreas {Maorschalk] and John Spratt. 1 p., 1737 Jan. 15 (Box 8)
  - #10, Grant to James Smith. 1 p., 1720 (Box 8)
  - #11, Land transaction, Patrick McKnight. 1 p., 1719 (Box 8)
  - #12, Land Grant to Patrick [Hume]. 1 p., 1721 Nov. 23 (Box 8)
  - #13, Indenture John Roberts and wife, Dorothy, and George Harrison. 2 pp., 1750 June 15 (Box 8)
  - #14, Indenture of Lease and Indenture of Release, William Gatehouse and wife, Mary. Attached document regarding recovery of debts in "his Majesty's Plantations and Colonies in America,". 4 pp., 1778 Nov. (Box 9)